Guide to the UH Core Advisory Committee Records 2015-021
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
UH Core Advisory Committee Records
1966-1992
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
2015-021
University of Houston Libraries
1 Linear Feet
The UH Core Advisory Committee Records document the development of the University of Houston's Core Curriculum from 1966 to 1992. Materials include university self studies, task force and committee reports, core curriculum documents, and undergraduate council minutes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for Research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Biographical / Historical
University of Houston Provost George Magner established the Core Advisory Committee in 1982 to implement and supervise a new undergraduate core curriculum. Over the next three and a half years, the committee considered 273 courses submitted by the various schools and departments of the university, eventually approving 157 for inclusion in the core. The committee issued its final report in July 1985, transferring responsibility for implementing and supervising the core curriculum to Undergraduate Council.
Custodial History
Materials were transferred to Special Collections in 2015.
Scope and Contents
The UH Core Advisory Committee Records document the development of the University of Houston's Core Curriculum from 1966 to 1992. Materials include university self studies, task force and committee reports, core curriculum documents, and undergraduate council minutes.
- University of Houston Self Studies, 1966-1976
  - UH Self Study, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - UH Self Study, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - UH Mission Self Study Report, December 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Self Study News Clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Admissions, Retention, and Enrollment Policy Documents, 1974-1998
  - University Council regarding Academic Bankruptcy, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Final Report on the Task Force on Admissions and Retention, Fall 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Final Report of the Task Force on Admissions and Retention with Summary of Responses, Fall 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - UH Undergraduate Admissions Policies, Fall 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Interim Report of the UH Enrollment Management Task Force, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - RARMGT - Enrollment Management, January 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Core Curriculum Documents, 1978-1992
  - UH Undergraduate Core Curriculum, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Core Curriculum from Final Report, June 1, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Final Report of the Core Advisory Committee, July 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 50 Hours: A Core Curriculum for College Students, October 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - UH Undergraduate Core Curriculum, Fall 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Undergraduate Council Minutes, 1984-1992
  - 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 17-24)